cpmadvisors.com 2013-12-05

# Optimal | Social Advertising - Recommendation and Analysis

### Privacy Policy

The following describes the overall company practices of optimal, Inc. including all subsidiaries, affiliates and network (referred to as “optimal”, “we”, “us”, or “our”). This Privacy Policy was created to let you know what information we collect when you visit our web sites (including but not limited to optim.al, optimalsocial.com, and CPMatic.com) and when we serve advertisements on our network of websites, why we collect it and how it is used. 

* * *

### What Information Is Collected?

###### Non-Personally Identifiable Consumer Data

optimal may collect anonymous data while you are visiting a optimal Web site or the Web site of one of optimal’s business customers, including advertisers and Web publishers (collectively “Business Customers”). This anonymous data includes information such as a web visitor’s IP address, web pages which have been viewed by a web visitor, date and time, domain type, and responses by a web visitor to an advertisement delivered by us or a third party advertising technology vendor. We, and/or a third party advertising technology vendor, may use different types of technologies to collect this type of information, including cookies and pixels. 

These cookie-based technologies allow us and our advertisers to better target advertising to user interests, and provide other benefits for example, to limit any person seeing a given advertisement too many times. If you want to opt-out of receiving targeted advertising that uses anonymous browser cookies, please [click here](http://optim.al/opt-out).

###### Personally Identifiable Consumer Data (PII)

To date, on our wholly owned properties we do not ask for personally identifiable information other than outlined below for business purposes. At some of optimal’s partner properties, people may be asked to register and provide personally identifiable data. optimal is committed to making sure that our partners provide notice and choice to all consumers. 

###### Other Information that is Collected

At some optimal properties, including this one, optimal collects personal information on individuals and companies who want to enter into business relationships with optimal (“business information”). An example of this would include web publishers who want to become a part of optimal’s web advertising network. We maintain business information for purposes of administering the program, such as maintaining account information and sending payments. We may share business information with third parties who provide administrative services (and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information), as well as pursuant to a court order or to law enforcement or government officials as we deem necessary or appropriate. 

* * *

### How Is Such Information Used?

optimal will use your non-personal information in order to better target advertisements and offers across the optimal network, to provide aggregate reporting to advertisers and clients, and to improve our advertising systems and products. In addition, that data may be combined with information collected from other sources so that we may better serve consumer preferences with offers that may be of interest to them. We may also share non-personally identifiable information with our subsidiaries and third party partners for similar use. If a consumer elects to provide optimal with personally identifiable data, we may utilize such data for marketing purposes. In addition, that data may be combined with information collected from other sources to better serve consumers with offers that may be of interest to them. For example, you may register for a newsletter and provide us with your email, If a consumer elects to provide us with personally identifiable data, he or she has the right to tell us not to make some of the uses of such data described herein or may have such data deleted in its entirety at any time. Please note that we will need you to provide your email address or other previously provided personal identifier in order to identify you in the Data Opt Out process. Also, please remember that if you choose to delete your information completely you will no longer receive the service in question. We collect PII from customers who are individuals or companies that wish to enter into business relationships with optimal, including websites and online marketers. This customer information is used only for purposes of administering these relationships, including maintaining account information, managing payments and communicating with the client. optimal may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on optimal; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of optimal; or (3) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of optimal, its websites or the public; 4) To provide updates and services that may be of interest to the customer. 

###### Security

optimal uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to optimal and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, optimal makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. 

* * *

### Additional Notices and Disclosures

###### Third Party Information Gathering

Our website may contain content and advertisements from third parties that may perform user activity tracking other than that described herein. These other sites may place their own cookies on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information. With regards to this potential third party data collection activity, optimal adheres to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising (OBA Principles). For more information about the OBA Principles and how to “opt-out” from third party data collection, please click [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices). Our website may also contain links to other websites on the Web. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by optimal. 

###### Correspondence

If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence and we may collect your email address. 

###### Children’s Privacy

optimal is very sensitive to the issue of children’s privacy. optimal’s websites, products, and services are neither developed for, nor directed at, children. If you believe your child has provided optimal with personally identifiable data, or registered at one of optimal’ websites, and you would like to have the data removed, please contact us. 

###### Sale of Assets

In the event that another company acquires all or substantially all of the assets related to the business, we reserve the right to include any or all stored personal information among the assets transferred to the acquiring company. 

###### Changes to Privacy Policy

This privacy policy is subject to change without notice. We may change our policy at any time by posting a new version of it on our website. 

###### Effective Date

The privacy policy was last revised on March 24th, 2010. 

* * *

### Questions and Comments

Questions and comments about this privacy policy should be submitted via the contact us form on this website or mailed to: **Optimal, Inc. 100 Bush Street, Suite 780 San Francisco, CA 94104**
